EDWIN RISVIANTO

Yogyakarta, ID · +6285155022840 erisvianto@gmail.com · LinkedIn: Edwin Risvianto · Github: Risviantoe

Fresh graduate from Amikom University Yogyakarta majoring in Informatics Engineering with a GPA of 3.89/4 who have an interest in the field of Web Development. In the same field, I have internship experience at PT. Media Kreasi Abadi and GCM Foundation as FrontEnd Developer where I am responsible for building the website interface according to the desired design It has been designed by a UI designer with ReactJS framework. Able to use framework CSS Bootstrap and PHP framework Laravel.

EXPERIENCE

FEB 2022 - JUL 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, PT MEDIA KREASI ABADI

- Responsible for brainstorming, developing, testing, collaborating, code reviewing, deploying, bug bashing, and launching frontend feature in a team. (React, Typescript, CSS, Context API).
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX design.
- Lead and assign tasks to the team so that the work can be completed according to the target time. (Microsoft Planner)
- Integrate the API that has been created by the backend division so that the website can be used functionally. (Axios)
- Pitching to stakeholders and mentors.

JAN 2022 - JUL 2022

BACKEND DEVELOPER – PART TIME, GCM FOUNDATION

- Develop an online exam website with various types of questions and answers. (Laravel)
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX design and define tasks to delegate to other engineers.
- Designing the API as needed to be consumed on the frontend.
- Integrate the API on the frontend to make it work as intended. (React, Axios)

JAN 2022 - JUL 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER – INTERNSHIP, GCM FOUNDATION

- Design the login page according to the briefing by the company CEO. (Figma).
- Developing authentication systems on various blended learning websites under the auspices of Geschool. (React, Bootstrap).

EDUCATION

OCT 2022

DIPLOMA OF INFORMATICS ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITAS AMIKOM YOGYAKATA

Cumulative GPA: 3.89/4.0 | Focus on majoring in Web Development.

JUL 2018

COMPUTER AND NETWORK ENGINEERING, SMK N 1 BANTUL

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React Js
- Laravel

- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- SASS
- Git

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

2020 - NOW

IKATAN MUDA MUDI MERTOSANAN KULON

TREASURER

• Provide maximum impact in the implementation of work programs by accelerating transparent and effective budget distribution.

2020 - 2021

HIMPUNAN MAHASISWA DIPLOMA INFORMATIKA

VICE CHAIRMAN

 Responsible for coordinating the division coordinator and replacing the chairman's duties when absent.

2020 - 2021

IKATAN MAHASISWA BIDIKMISI AMIKOM

MEMBER OF THE SOCIAL DIVISION

• Take an active role in community service by collaborating directly with many parties.